Guide to the Coleman Dowell Papers 1925-1985 MSS 036
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Published and Unpublished Works
  - Subseries A: Novels, Short Stories and Other Writings
    - The Houses of Children [ms.] (part 1: p. i-iii, 1-138): ca. 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Houses of Children [ms.] (part 2: p. 139-220) ca. 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Houses of Children [ed. draft 1]: 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Houses of Children [ed. draft 2]: 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Houses of Children [Afterword by Bradford Morrow]: 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Houses of Children [Show proof]: 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Houses of Children [reviews]: 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - White on Black on White [galley proof. p.1-125]: 1983 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - White on Black on White [galley proof. p.126-251]: 1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - The Silver Swanne [unbound copy]: 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - The Silver Swanne [unbound copy]: 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Houses of Children [galley proof (revise) ]: 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Houses of Children [galley proof (revise) ]: 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Houses of Children [annotated galley proof]: 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Autobiography [fragments] n.d., undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - A Dark Book [later, A Star Bright Lie] [ts] n.d., undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - A Dark Book [1st draft] n.d., undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Memoir about Carl Van Vechten n.d., undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - What I Did On My Vacation n.d., undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Willow's Story] n.d., undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Eve of the Green Grass n.d., undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [fragments] n.d., undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Discards? Edited] n.d., undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - And What of the Valley? n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Black Conductor n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Boy n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Boy of My Dreams n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Cat n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Chris n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Dedication & Elegy (to Tam): ca. 1978 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Diary of a Bigot n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - The Dory [formerly, The Gag & Puke] n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - The Geisha n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - I Am n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - The Indian Giver n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - The Intruder n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Ivy: n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Jenny Come Home [Bobby Dowell aged 12] ca.: 1949 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - The Landlords n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Liars Cookbook n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - The Long Weekend n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Mademoiselle du Paris n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Maya [see also, Up at Claudo's] n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Moetter n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Writing (1): 1968, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Writing (2) n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Writing (3) n.d., undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous Writing (4): 1985, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Old Woman in a Garden: ca. 1962 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - The Other Room n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Poems A-G: 1964, 1982, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Poems H-L n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Poems M-R: 1960, 1964, 1978, 1979, n.d., 1960-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Poems S-Z n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Poems: Miscellaneous n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Polish Story n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Snap n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - The Twenties n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Up at Claudo's n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Untitled ["I have wanted to see three things"]: 1965 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Untitled ["It was the day he arranged..."] n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Untitled ["It's the noise"] n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Untitled ["Men go to work."] n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Untitled ["My first editor"] n.d., undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Yetta Arenstein Memorial: 1965 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Subseries B: Plays and Dramatic Pieces
    - Gentle Laurel [later, Eve of the Green Grass]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Gentle Laurel [later, Eve of the Green Grass]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [ms.]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Eve of the Green grass [notes and fragments]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Act 1 and background notes]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Revised by Bert Slaff]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Act 1&2 and notes]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Act 1&2 and explanatory notes], 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [Act 1. Incomplete]. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Eve of the Green Grass [correspondence & writings]. 1962, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Ah, Wilderness [newspaper article]: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Beautiful Dreamer [C. Dowell?]. 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Beautiful Dreamer [variant version] [1959], undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Call back April: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Chloe: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cora's Pill: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - The Crystal Tree [by Coleman Dowell?]: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - The Crystal tree [by Doris Julian]. 1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Great Godalmighty Bird n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Haymarket [musical play]. 1958 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - The Indian Giver: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Little Maggie: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Mrs October Was Here: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Paul and Paul's Super Ego: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - The Penthouse: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Shangri-La: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Sleeping Rock: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Tropicana: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Untitled murder mystery: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Series III: Musical Works and Lyrics
  Series III: Musical Works and Lyrics, spans the years from the 1950s to 1960s. The bulk of the material falls in the year 1961 when Dowell's largest theatrical work, The Tattooed Countess, opened on Broadway. The work contains book, lyrics, and score by Dowell and signifies the major effort of his theatrical production. Dowell's second largest musical effort, Haymarket, although unfinished, also contains a large number of musical works and lyrics. Most of Dowell's theatrical works are heavily annotated. The lists of song titles included in this material provide an opportunity to study Dowell's creative processes, as he changed or reworked his material. It is not unusual to find a lyric assigned to one of Dowell's musicals also appearing in another of his theatrical works.
  Dowell's music and lyrics from the 1950-1953 television series, Once Upon A Tune, are included in the Collection. Although Dowell composed nearly one thousand songs for the weekly broadcast of this show over its run, most of these are not included in his papers.
  Box 1 - Barcode: 31142042236839 Box 2 - Barcode: 31142042236847 Box 3 - Barcode: 31142042236755 Box 4 - Barcode: 31142042236763 Box 5 - Barcode: 31142042236771
  - Ah, Wilderness!: n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Haymarket Lyrics: n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Haymarket Sheet Music: n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lida Questa: n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Lyrics: n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Musical Works: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Music from C. Dowell's Library: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Musical Collaborations: n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Once Upon A Tune. 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Streisand Material. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Reeds). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Horns). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Cello). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Harp). 1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Piano). 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Vocals). 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Entre Acte/Orch. parts masters) 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Book). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Book). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Book photocopy) 1961 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Book with revisions). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Correspondence). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Telegrams). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Clippings). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Playbills). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Tattooed Countess (Set transparencies). 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Works by Others and Miscellaneous Materials
  Series IV: Writings by Others and Miscellaneous Materials, contains photographs of Coleman Dowell, family members and other individuals. Correspondence is interfiled with typescripts, plays, novels, short stories, poems, etc., written by other people.
  Box 1 - Barcode: 31142042236813 Box 2 - Barcode: 31142042236821
  - Correspondence 1982-1984 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 1)
  - Above the Chautaquas [ms.]. 1984 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 2)
  - The American Baedeker of Mateo Lupi [ms.]: n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 3)
  - Contrapposto [ms.]: n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 4)
  - Cutt's Grace [ms.] [see also, Who Else I Don't Like]. 1984 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 5)
  - The History of It [ms.]: n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 6)
  - Hung Storm [ms.]. 1982 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 7)
  - Papa Itzhak (1) [ms.]: n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 8)
  - Papa Itzhak (2) [ms.] n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 9)
  - Post Partum [ms.] (2 versions): n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 10)
  - Who Else I Don't Like [ms.] [see also, Whom No Hate...]. 1984 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 11)
  - Whom No Hate Stirs None Dances [ms.] [see also, Who Else...]: n.d., undated (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 12)
  - Printed Material. 1982, 1983, 1984, 1985, n.d., 1982-1985 (Box 1 [Bradford Morrow], Folder 13)
  - Adams, Jody [ms.] [The No-Name Blues]: n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 1)
  - Arnold, Kenneth. [mss.] [Better Homes and Gardens; She Also Dances]. 1980, n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 2)
  - Deba: n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 3)
  - For Sukey T. (author unknown) [ms.] [1974/75], undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 4)
  - Hines, Glen: "For Coleman" [ms. poem]. 1979 (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 5)
  - Kuehl, John and Linda Kandel Kuehl [An Interview with Coleman Dowell]. 1979 (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 6)
  - Laughlin, James [ms. & printed material]. 1974, 1978, n.d. (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 7)
  - Martin, Stephen: A Comparative Study in Androgyny in 1984. Twentieth-Century Literature [ms. & corresp.] (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 8)
  - Martin, Stephen-Paul [Excorcism and Grace]: n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 9)
  - Masseaux, Brett [ms.] [Maybe at the Next Station...]: n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 10)
  - Schneider, Louise [ts.] [Orphaned Children of the Orphaned South]. 1968 (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 11)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert [mss. and printed material]. 1984, 1985, n.d. (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 12)
  - Unidentified writings: n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 13)
  - Van Vechten, Carl [printed material] 1960, n.d. (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 14)
  - White, Edmund: Caracole [ms.] (pp. 1-216): n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 15)
  - White, Edmund: Caracole [ms.] (pp. 217-426): n.d., undated (Box 2 [Works by Others], Folder 16)
  - White, Edmund: A Man of the World [ms.]. n.d., undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - White, Edmund (Printed Matter). 1979, 1980, 1981, 1984, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Clippings. 1968 1973, n.d. (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 3)
  - Dowell Family Genealogy. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 4)
  - French lessons with Yvette Arenstein. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 5)
  - Italian lessons. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 6)
  - Legal documents. 1956, 1957, 1962, 1968, 1970, n.d., 1956-1970 (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 7)
  - Misc. notes, literary sketches & quotes. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 8)
  - Printed and pictorial matter. 1961, 1965, 1976, 1980, 1961-1980 (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 9)
  - Photos: C. Dowell and Family. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 10)
  - Photos: Others. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 11)
  - Reviews by C. Dowell. 1977, 1979, 1985, n.d., 1977-1985 (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 12)
  - Reviews & Articles about C. Dowell and his work. 1974, 1976, 1977, n.d., 1974-1977 (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 13)
  - The Tattooed Countess [framed newspaper ad for the musical]. 1961 (Box 3 [Misc.], Folder 14)
  - Bibliography [of C. Dowell's work by Bertram Slaff]. n.d., undated (Box 3 [Addenda], Folder 15)
  - Morrow, Bradford [Coleman Dowell Obituary]. 1985 (Box 3 [Addenda], Folder 16)
  - Karl, F. [The Faulknerian Presence in Contemporary American Fiction]. 1987 (Box 3 [Addenda], Folder 17)
  - Kuehl, Linda K. and John R. [Prospectus for A Star-Bright Lie: Coleman Dowell's Theatrical Memoirs]. 1989 (Box 3 [Addenda], Folder 18)
  - Printed Material [New Directions' Fiftieth Anniversary]. 1986 (Box 3 [Addenda], Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous Oversize
  - Posters, newspapers, scrapbook, etc.
    - The Tattooed Countess poster. 1961 (Box 4)
    - The Tattooed Countess set design (watercolor). 1961 (Box 4)
    - Misc. newspapers 1968, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Mrs. October Was Here: scrapbook of reviews. 1974 (Box 4)
    - Ink drawing on placemat by Hugh Dilworth (?). 1962 (Box 4)
  - Books and Other Printed Materials from Coleman Dowell's Library
    - Abrams, Linsey. Charting the Stars. New York: 1979 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft, Mary. Autobiography of a Spy. New York: 1983 (Box 4)
    - Bax, Martin. The Hospital Ship. New York: 1976 (Box 4)
    - Beeson, Jack. To a Lady Who Asked for a Cypher [sheet music]. New York: 1970 (Box 4)
    - Britton, Burt, ed. Self-Portrait: Book People Picture Themselves. New York: 1976 (Box 4)
    - Colum, P. & Cabell, M.F., eds. Between Friends: Letters of James Branch Cabell and Others, New York: 1962 (Box 4)
    - Dunphy, Jack. An Honest Woman. New York: 1971 (Box 4)
    - Dunphy, Jack. Nightmovers. New York: 1967 (Box 4)
    - Eliot, Elizabeth. Heiresses and Coronets. New York: 1959 (Box 4)
    - Elmslie, Kenward. Moving Right Along Calais, VT: 1980 (Box 4)
    - Geva, Tamara. Split Seconds. New York: 1972 (Box 4)
    - Goldman, Michael. At the Edge. New York: 1969 (Box 4)
    - Goldman, Michael. First Poems. New York: 1966 (Box 4)
    - Greene, Jonathan. Scaling the Walls Lexington, KY: 1974 (Box 4)
    - Gunn, Thom. Moly and My Sad Captains. New York: 1973 (Box 4)
    - Gunn, Thom. The Passages of Joy. New York: 1982 (Box 4)
    - Gunn, Thom.. Selected Poems: 1950-1975 London: 1979, 1950-1979 (Box 4)
    - Hunter, Kim. Loose in the Kitchen. North Hollywood: 1975 (Box 4)
    - Kuehl, John. The Fool-Spy. New York: 1967 (Box 4)
    - Kuehl, John. John Hawkes and the Craft of Conflict. New Brunswick, NJ: 1975 (Box 4)
    - Kuehl, J. & Moore, S., eds. In Recognition of William Gaddis Syracuse, NY: 1984 (Box 4)
    - Latouche, John. Ballet Ballads [music]. New York: 1949 (Box 4)
    - Laughlin, James. In Another Country San Francisco: 1978 (Box 4)
    - Lauterback, Ann. Closing Hours. New York: 1983 (Box 4)
    - Lauterback, Ann. The Dark Door. New York: 1985 (Box 4)
    - Lauterback, Ann. Sacred Weather. New York: 1984 (Box 4)
    - McClure, Michael. Scratching the Beat Surface San Francisco: 1982 (Box 4)
    - McClure, Michael., undated (Box 4)
    - Martin, Stephen. Edges. New York: 1978 (Box 4)
    - Morrow, Bradford. After a Charme. New York: 1984 (Box 4)
    - Morrow, Bradford. Posthumes. New York: 1982 (Box 4)
    - Morrow, Bradford. The Preferences. New York: 1983 (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James. Children is All. New York: 1961 (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James. Color of Darkness and Children is All. New York: 1965 (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James. Colour of Darkness London: 1961 (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James. I Am Elijah Thrush London: 1972 (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James.. Malcolm. New York: [1959] (Box 4)
    - Purdy, James. The Runnning Sun. New York: 1971 (Box 4)
    - Rexroth, Kenneth. Selected Poems ed. by Bradford Morrow. New York: 1984 (Box 4)
    - Roster, Norman. Thrive Upon the Rock. New York: 1965 (Box 4)
    - Scott, Zachary. John Emory. New York: 1965 (Box 4)
    - Segalen, Victor. Stelae trans. by Nathaniel Tarn. Santa Barbara: 1969 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. [presentations], undated (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. The Bat-Poet / Randall Jarrell. New York: 1964 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Fantasy Sketches Philadelphia: 1970 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. The Griffin and the Minor Canon / Frank Stockton. New York: 1963 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Higglety Pigglety Pop! New York: 1967 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. In the Night Kitchen. New York: 1970 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. The Light Princess / George MacDonald. New York: 1969 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Lullabies and Night Songs / Alec Wilder. New York: 1964 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Nikolenka's Childhood / Leo Tolstoy. New York: 1963 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Poems from William Blake's "Songs of Innocence" / William Blake. London: 1967 (Box 4)
    - Sendak, Maurice, illus. Sarah's Room / Doris Orgel. New York: 1963 (Box 4)
    - Sobin, Gustaf. Caesure: Midsummer Plymouth, UK: 1981 (Box 4)
    - Sobin, Gustaf. Celebration of the Sound Through. New York: 1982 (Box 4)
    - Sobin, Gustaf. Ten Sham Haikus. New York: 1983 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Aberration of Starlight. New York: 1980 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Blue Pastoral San Francisco: 1983 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. A Dozen Oranges Santa Barbara: 1976 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Imaginative Qualities of Actual Things. New York: 1971 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Mulligan Stew. New York: 1979 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. The Orangery Austin, TX: 1978 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Selected Poems: 1958-1980 Santa Barbara: 1981, 1958-1981 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. Something Said San Francisco: 1984 (Box 4)
    - Sorrentino, Gilbert. White Sail Santa Barbara: 1977 (Box 4)
    - Stein, Gertrude. Alphabets and Birthdays. New Haven: 1957 (Box 4)
    - Stein, Gertrude. A Novel of Thank You / Carl Van Vechten, ed. New Haven: 1958 (Box 4)
    - Van Vechten, Carl. The Blind Bow-Boy. New York: 1923 (Box 4)
    - Van Vechten, Carl.. Fire Crackers. New York: 1925 (Box 4)
    - Van Vechten, Carl.. Peter Whiffle: His Life and Works. New York: 1927 (Box 4)
    - [Van Vechten, Carl] The American Record Guide June 1960 (Box 4)
    - [Van Vechten, Carl] The American Record Guide June 1960. A Bibliography / compiled by Klaus W. Jonas. New York: 1955, 1955-1960 (Box 4)
    - [Van Vechten, Carl] The American Record Guide June 1960. Carl Van Vechten; 1880 - 1964 San Francisco: 1965, 1960-1965 (Box 4)
    - [Van Vechten, Carl] The American Record Guide June 1960. Carl Van Vechten and the Twenties / E. Lueders. Albuquerque: 1955, 1955-1960 (Box 4)
    - [Van Vechten, Carl] The American Record Guide June 1960. 80 Writers...in Honor of His 80th Birthday, 17 June 1960. New Haven: 1960 (Box 4)
    - Vanity Fair: Selections. New York: 1960 (Box 4)
    - White, Edmund. A Boy's Own Story. New York: 1982 (Box 4)
    - White, Edmund. Forgetting Elena. New York: 1973 (Box 4)
    - Whitmore, George. Getting Gay in New York. New York: 1976 (Box 4)
    - Yutang, Lin. Imperial Peking. New York: 1961 (Box 4)
    - Zinnes, Harriet I Wanted to See Something Flying. New York: 1976 (Box 4)
  - Periodicals
    - Adena. Vol. 5, no. 1, Spring 1980 (Box 4)
    - Ambit. Vols. 61, 65, 69, 73, 76, 79, 84, 88, 89, 94, 100: 1975-1985. (Box 4)
    - Bomb: Artists, Writers, Actors, Directors. No. 10, Fall 1984 (Box 4)
    - Bomb: Artists, Writers, Actors, Directors. No. 13, Fall 1985 (Box 4)
    - Bomb: Artists, Writers, Actors, Directors. No. 34, Winter 1991. (Box 4)
    - Conjunctions. Vols. 3-6, 8, 9: New York: 1982-1986. (Box 4)
    - Contemporary Literature. Vol. 22, No. 3, Summer 1981 (Box 4)
    - Frankfurter Hefte. 17 Jahrang, Heft 4, April 1962 (Box 4)
    - New Directions. Vols. 26-33, 35-36, 50., undated (Box 4)
    - Review of Contemporary Fiction. Vol. 2, no. 2, Bowles & Dowell number, undated (Box 4)
    - Review of Contemporary Fiction. Vol. 4, no. 1, Burroughs number, undated (Box 4)
    - Review of Contemporary Fiction. Vol. 6, no. 2, Fiction Issue, undated (Box 4)
    - The Writer. March 1968. (Box 4)
- Accretion 2008 - Series I: Correspondence
  This series contains a small amount of correspondence between Dowell and various friends and publishers. Those folders labeled "Miscellaneous Letters" contain photocopies, primarily of letters written by Dowell to his family members, collected posthumously by Bertram Slaff. The series also contains correspondence between Slaff and others regarding Dowell's death.
  - D'Amico, Maria Vittoria, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dahl, Gunnar Andreas, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dunphy, Jack, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fitzgerald, G., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    General note
    Contains one hand-addressed, empty envelope.
  - Frankfurter Hefte, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Froman, Jane, 1957, 1959, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Glassgold, Peter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Herlie, Eileen, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hoepffner, Bernard, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kaldheim, Peter, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kroll, Lucy, 1995, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Landskoff-Yorck, Ruth, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Laughlin, James, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Low, Betty, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mielziner, Joe, 1953, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Letters (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Primarily photocopies of letters composed by Dowell, mostly written to members of his family.
  - Miscellaneous Letters (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Prager, Robert, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rakoff, Vivian M., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Rejection Letters from Publishers, 1971, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - S. Fischer Verlag, Publishers, 1962-63, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Semmons, Hella, 1968-1984, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Sendak, Maurice, 1967-1971, 1973, 1975, 1978, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Contains one letter and numerous hand-addressed, empty envelopes.
  - Slaff, Bertram, 1955-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Accretion 2008 - Series II: Published and Unpublished Works
  The primary focus of Accretion 2008 Series II is Bertram Slaff's attempts to publish Dowell's journal, which Slaff titled An American Eccentric. Slaff edited the journal entries, and arranged them thematically. The folders in this series reflect the various iterations of these arrangements. There is also a manuscript of edited journal entries specifically surrounding Dowell's relationship with his dachsund, which Slaff titled Cole and Tam - A Writer and His Dog. The series also contains various published and unpublished materials, including photocopies of Dowell's suicide note and will.
  Conditions Governing Access